Finding Aid for the John Cope Caldwell Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Wieck, Fred, (23); Mar. 24, 1953, Apr. 2, 1953, Apr. 8, 1953, Apr. 9, 1953 Apr. 14, 1953, May 8) 1953, May 14, 1953, June 5, 1953, June 8, 1953, June 10, 1953, June 15, 1953, June 18, 1953 July 17, 1953, July 22, 1953, Sept. 29, 1953, Oct. 2, 1953, Oct. 14, 1953, Oct. 20, 1953, Nov. 17, 1953, Nov. 27, 1953, Dec. 2, 1953, Jan. 20, 1954, Jan. 28, 1954; 10
Wilcox, A. C ., (1); n.d.; 10
Wiley, Don C., (2); Sept. 24, 1959, Oct. 9, 1959; 10
Wilkins, Charles E., (2); Aug. 11, 1957, Aug. 21, 1957; 10
Williams, D ., (1); Apr. 4, 1957; 10
Willoughby, C. A., to Henry Regnery, (1); Aug. 22, 1952; 10
Wilson, Donald E., (1); Apr. 30, 1963; 10
Wilson, Kenneth L ., (16); Oct. 29, 1953, Nov. 12, 1953, Jan. 21, 1954, Mar. 2, 1954, Mar. 17, 1954, June 4, 1954, Jan. 4, 1955, Apr. 15, 1955, Apr. 22, 1955, July 8, 1955, Oct. 26, 1955 Mar. 6, 1956, June 8, 1956, Aug. 8, 1957, Aug. 13, 1957, Nov. 7, 1957; 10
Wimbush, P. J. B., (1); Dec. 5, 1957; 10
Winfield, Gerald F., (1); Aug. 20, 1956; 10
Winston, Ann Caulfeild, (1); Sept. 12, 1956; 10
Wise, Rebecca, (1); Nov. 19, 1952; 10
Woodliff, Laura J., (1); Dec. 12, 1956; 10
Wright, Edward A ., (1); Mar. 10, 1958; 10
Wright, Mary C., (1); June 9, 1952; 10
Wright, William S., (5); July 10, 1956, July 7, 1959, Feb. 17, 1960, Sept. 4, 1960, July 3, 1967; 10
Wu, K. T., (1); Aug. 8, 1957; 10
Wysham, William N., (1); Jan. 9, 1953; 10
Y
Yang, M. K ., (1); n.d.; 10
Yang, You Chan, (1); Dec. 2, 1955jl 10
Yao, Shuang Jeff, (2); Nov. 25, 1958, Jan. 20, 1959; 10
Yeh, George K. C., (3); July 15, 1960, Feb. 5, 1958, Sept. 2, 1960; 10
Yokota, I., to Richard J. Walsh, Jr. (1); July 24, 1959; 10
Yoo, Chin Hyong, (1); Nov. 29, 1961; 10
Yoo, Dae Joon, (1); Jan. 31, 1958; 10
Young, M. Norvel, (1); Oct. 4, 1955; 10
Young, Mildred T. (1); July 29, 1952; 10
Yunker, Ruth, (1); June 12, 1956; 10
Z
Zimmerman, Jules M ., (2); n.d., n.d.; 10
INDEX 2 JOHN COPE CALDWELL
This is a name index of the correspondents of John and Elsie Caldwell. The figure (or figures) in parentheses immediately following each name denotes the total number of letters from that person in the collection; the dates are for the time of the letters. The full name of the writer is given whenever possible; 1 letter is without a surname. The signature on this letter is Paul. The last number given refers to the box in which the correspondence may be found.
B
Berger, Marcella, (1); Oct. 26, 1967; 25
Bevelheimer, Paul F., Jr., (1); Feb. 19, 1966; 25
Blake, Beth, (3); July 21, 1965, Aug. 22, 1965, July 22, 1966; 25
Bretall, R. F., (1); Aug. 2, 1966; 25
Butler, Joan, (44); Mar. 2, 1966, June 29, 1966, June 30 (1966), July 8, 1966, July 15, 1966, July 22, 1966, July 29, 1966, Aug. 2, 1966, Aug. 12, 1966, Aug. 19, 1966, Aug. 29, 1966, Sept. 1, 1966, Sept. 2, 1966, Oct. 5, 1966, Oct. 12, 1966, Oct. 13, 1966, Oct. 17, 1966, Oct. 28, 1966, Dec. 7, 1966, Dec. 15, 1966, Jan. 16, 1967, Feb. 7, 1967, Feb. 13, 1967, Feb. 23, 1967, Mar. 2, 1967, Mar. 21, 1978, Mar. 28, 1967, May 15, 1967, June 15, 1967, July 17, 1967, July 24, 1967, July 25, 1967, July 27, 1967, Aug. 24, 1967, Aug. 28, 1967, Sept. 29, 1967, Oct. 6, 1967, Oct. 9, 1967, Oct. 16, 1967, Oct. 19, 1967, Oct. 20, 1967, Nov. 13, 1967", Nov. 20, 1967, Nov. 30, 1967; 25
C
Christman, Elizabeth, (1); July 14, 1967; 25
D
Dietz, Betty Warner, (13); Aug. 3, 1966, Nov. 21, 1966, Dec. 5, 1966, Jan. 19, 1967, Jan. 27, 1967, Jan. 28, 1967, Feb. 1, 1967, Feb. 11, 1967, Feb. 25, 1967, Mar. 3, 1967, Mar. 9, 1967, Mar. 13, 1967, Mar. 20, 1967; 25
E
Ewald, Barbara, (3); Aug. 6, (n.d.), (n.d.), (n.d.); 25
F
Federico, Grace, (6) 7 Feb. 28, 1966, Mar. 16, 1966, June 24, 1966, July 26, 1966, Sept. 13, 1966, Feb. 24, 1967; 25
G
Galinski, Naomi, (3)7 Aug. 15, 1967 (to Joan Butler), Nov. 25, 1966 (to Richard J. Walsh, Jr.), Dec. 2, 1966(to Richard J. Walsh, Jr.); 25
Gordon, Erwin E., (1); Aug. 4, 1965; 25
H
Hutchinson, Sally-Lou, (1); July 6, 1966; 25
J
John Day Company Inc., (1); (n.d.); 25
K
Kopacz, Sandra, (1); Sept. 22 1966; 25
M
Mazzucco, Marcella, (2); Mar. 7, 1967, July 13, 1967; 25
Mutsu, Ian, (14); Aug. 11, 1966, Sept. 27, 1966, Oct. 6, 1966, Oct. 8, 1966, Jan. 20, 1967, Jan. 23, 1967, Jan. 30, 1967, Mar. 5, 1967, Mar. 7, 1967, Mar. 9, 1967, Mar. 9, 1967, Mar. 28, 1967, Aug. 5, 1967, (n.d.); 25
O
Okuda, Nadkazu, (1); Mar. 30, 1967; 25
S
Sobstad, Sandra, (1); June 22, 1967; 25
Sparke, Eric, (1); Aug. 17, 1966; 25
Sullivan, Barbara, (1); Nov. 16, 1967 (to Richard J. Walsh, Jr.); 25
Suntarovat, Sirisak, (1); Dec. 27, 1966; 25
T
Thomson, Marcelline E., (1); Sept. 6, 1966; 25
W
Walsh, Mary 0., (12); Jan. 3, 1966, June 23, 1966, July 8, 1966, Aug. 9, 1966, Aug. 24, 1966, Aug. 24, 1966, Oct. 6, 1966, Nov. 22, 1966, Feb. 8, 1967, Apr. 6, 1967, June 5, 1967, June 22, 1967; 25
Walsh, Richard J., Jr., (81); July 16, 1965, Aug. 3, 1965, Sept. 8, 1965, Sept. 17, 1965, Dec. 14, 1965, Feb. 8, 1966, Feb. 18, 1966, Feb. 23, 1966, Mar. 4, 1966, Mar. 25, 1966, Mar. 29, 1966, May 16, 1966 May 16, 1966, May 17, 1966, May 28, 1966, June 1, 1966, June 1, 1966, June 7, 1966, June 9, 1966, June 9, 1966, June 10, 1966, June 14, 1966, June 14, 1966, June 20, 1966, June 21, 1966 June 28, 1966, July 1, 1966, July 8, 1966, July 19, 1966, July 21, 1966, July 22, 1966, July 29, 1966, Aug. 8, 1966, Aug, 10, 1966, Aug. 11, 1966, Aug. 15, 1966, Sept. 2, 1966, Sept. 9, 1966, Sept. 9, 1966, Sept. 16, 1966, Oct. 19, 1966, Nov. 4, 1966, Nov. 4, 1966, Nov. 22, 1966 (to Naomi Galinski), Dec. 6, 1966, Dec. 6, 1966, Dec. 13, 1966, Dec. 30, 1966, Jan. 31, 1967, Jan. 31, 1967, Feb. 8, 1967, Feb. 15, 1967, Feb. 23, 1967, Mar. 3, 1967, Mar. 21, 1967, Mar. 23, 1967, Mar. 31, 1967, Mar. 31, 1967, Apr. 7, 1967, Apr. 19, 1967, Apr. 21, 1967, June 9, 1967, June 15, 1967, June 15, 1967, June 15, 1967, June 20, 1967, July 8, 1967, July 10, 1967, July 13, 1967, July 14, 1967, July 14, 1967, July 18, 1967, July 21, 1967, July 25, 1967, July 27, 1967, July 31, 1967, Aug. 10, 1967, Aug. 24, 1967, Nov. 21, 1967 (to Barbara Sullivan), Dec. 18, 1967, Dec. 27, 1967; 25
Washam, Veronica, (2); Nov. 8, 1966, Feb. 27, 1967; 25
Letter With No Surname
Paul, (1); June 11, 1966; 25
INDEX 3 JOHN COPE CALDWELL
This is a name index of the correspondents of John and Elsie Caldwell. The figure (or figures) in parentheses immediately following each name denotes the total number of letters from that person in the collection; the dates are for the time of the letters. Three letters are without surname and are listed at the end. This correspondence is found in manuscript box 36.
A
Auburn, James E. (1) card postmarked March 30, 1967.
Abrahams, Johanna L. (1) Aug. 18, 1966.
B
Baker, Howard H., Jr. (1) Feb. 19, 1968.
Bauman, Carl (3) July 6, 1966; Aug. 10, 1966; April 22, 1969.
Bemis, Robert (1) July 23, 1965
Beresford, Juliet S. (1) Sept. 10, 1968
Bretall, Ron F. (1) July 28, 1966
Butler, Joan (5) Nov. 4, 1964; Dec. 15, 1964; Dec. 18, 1964; Dec. 28, 1964; Aug. 4, 1966.
C
Chaichalmongkol, Sittisah (1) Oct. 26, 1968
Cochran, Galdys L. (1) Nov. 26, 1968
Cornwall, Mrs. William (1) Jan. 18, 1968
Cretella, Anthony (1) n.d.
China Travel Service (1) April 9, 1969
Crothers, Jim (1) Oct. 4, 1968
Curran, Pauline L. (1) Sept. 20, 1969.
da Roza, M.L. (1) July 13, 1966.
Dat, K. C. (4) April 14, 1966; June 23, 1966; Aug. 8, 1966; Oct. 16, 1967.
Davis, Mindy (1) April 2, 1968.
Donnelly, Dixon (1) March 21, 1968.
E
Ebsworth, Barney A. (2) both dated Dec. 2, 1968.
Eidson, Kendall (1) Dec. 26, 1967.
Enzor, Travel Service (1) Nov. 6, 1968
Evans, Susan (1) June 20, 1966.
F
Fannemel, N. (1) Sept. 20, 1968.
Francisco, Mrs. E. (1) Nov. 12, 1968.
Fulton, Richard (1) Feb. 7, 1968.
G
Bore, Albert (3) Feb. 7, 1968; March 16, 1968; March 26, 1968
H
Hacker, Mrs. John W. (5) May 17, 1968; Aug..31, 1968; Sept. 9, 1968; Sept. 20, 1968; Nov. 11, 1968.
Healy, Laurin H. (1) Aug. 26, 1968.
Heiss, F. H. (1) March 28, 1968.
Hill, Roland (4) July 5, 1966; July 7, 1966; July 19, 1966; Aug. 16, 1966.
Holt, Andy D. (1) Sept. 1, 1968.
Howard, Shirley S. (Mrs. Donald G.) (1) Aug. 28, 1968.
K
Kedsiri, Kamol (1) Oct. 29, 1968.
Keedick, Robert (1) March 4, 1968.
Kohlrenken, James (1) Feb. 6, 1968.
L - M - P'
Larsen, Peter (1) Nov. 20, 1968.
Law, Kath Jarratt (1) n.d.
Lazzara, Janice (1) March 25, 1968.
Mackling, Mrs. Justin W. (Clara) (2) n.d.
Manigault, Debra (1) Jan. 12, 1968.
Manning, Gus (1) Sept. 5, 1968.
Miller, Mrs. Mattha (1) Sept, 25, 1968.
Mike, Mike K. (1) June 6, 1967.
McNair, Clyde (1) July 11, 1966.
Pandolfo, P. M. (1) June 28, 1966.
Plake, F. Marvin (2) June 24, 1968; July 3, 1968.
Pray, Martin B. (2) July 16, 1968; Oct. 31, 1968.
R
Rosario, Alberto (1) April 22, 1968
Rosenthal, Jerry E. (2) May 27, 1966; June 28, 1966.
S
Satterlee, Francis N. (1) July 9, 1965 plus carbon copy.
Schum, Mrs. Farra D. (1) May 4, 1968
Skinner, J. E. (1) April 13, 1968
Souers, Robert M. (1) May 22, 1968
Sullivan, A. G. (1) March 14, 1968
Sullivan, Barbara (1) April 23, 1969 - zeroxed copy of letter to Mrs. Grace Guerini
Sunlarovat, Sirisak (1) May 23, 1968
T
Tan, Raymond (1) June 10, 1968
W
Walsh, Mary 0. (1) Oct. 30, 1964
Walsh, Richard J., Jr. (6) June 12, 1964; Jan. 7, 1965; Jan. 18, 1965; March 12, 1965; March 16, 1965; Aug. 15, 1967; Aug. 16, 1967.
Wenkam, Robert (1) Nov. 21, 1968
Wiegard, Mary (1) Oct. 23, 1968
Woo, Jimmy (1) n.d.
Wright, R. J. (1) June 21, 1966
Unidentified
John? (1) Aug. 12, 1968
Roberta? (1) Oct. 15, n.d.
Ruth and family? (1) April 9, 1968
one zeroxed copy of letter
- Day-books, 1955 to 1960 and 1963 to 1964 (Box 1)
  14 small and 2 large day-books of Asian, African, and South American travels. Holograph. Three brief autobiographies(1951)- typescript and 2 biographies typescript. Travel schedules- 98 schedules from 1950 to 1962.
- Correspondence - Outgoing, August 3, 1943 - December 1, 1966 (Box 2 - 3)
  Outgoing correspondence of 569 letters, chronologically arranged by days and months. Letters are typewritten, carbon copies. Few are mimeographed. 36 undated letters.
- Correspondence - Incoming, 7 containers (Box 4 - 10)
  Incoming correspondnece of 3,022 letters, 30 telegrams, alphabetically arranged. Letters are typewritten. with the exception of a few Holograph. Few are carbon copies. There are 196 illegible and unsigned letters.
- News Reports, 1951-1953 (Box 11)
  Chronologically arranged by year. Articles and reports from Nashville, Tennessee, papers. Also numerous statements, which are typewritten, are included. These statements refer to activities of various government officials and Caldwell's opinion of these individuals. Also’ a statement of Communist activities before the Internal Security Commission.
  Magazine and Newspaper articles, material by Caldwell. Articles and short publications by Caldwell, dated and undated. Chronologically arranged by the year. Serial articles to brief references; mostly of social and political concerns.
- Unpublished articles - Articles by Caldwell; dated and undated. Chronologically arranged by years. Serial articles to brief references; mainly of social and political concerns. Typewritten and mimeographed. (Box 12 - 13)
- Book Drafts, gallies, and manuscripts. Books arranged alphabetically by titles. Typewritten, carbon copies. Family, The Clarke Story, Communism in Our World, The Eagle and his R.0.K.1s, Far East Travel Guide, Far Pacific Travel Guide, From Chiang Kai shek's Diaries, I Went to School in Red China, The Korea Story, Let's Visit America's Ambassadors, Let's Visit Argentina, Let's Visit Australia, Let's Visit Brazil, Let's Visit Canada, Let's Visit Central America, Let's Visit Ceylon, Let's Visit Chile, Let's Visit China, Let's Visit Columbia, Let's Visit India, Let's Visit Indonesia, Let's Visit Japan, Let's Visit Korea, Let's Visit Mexico, Let's Visit Middle East, Let's Visit New Zealand, Let's Visit Pakistan, Let's Visit Peru, Let's Visit the Philippines, Let's Visit the South Pacific, Let's Visit Southeast Asia, Let's Visit Thailand, Let's Visit Venezuela, Let's Visit Vietnam, Let's Visit West Africa, Let's Visit the West Indies, Ling Ceng and the Payoff, Manpogee, a Story of Korea, Our Neighbors in Africa, Our Neighbors in Brazil, Our Neighbors in India, Our Neighbors in Korea, Our Neighbors in Peru, The Overseas Chinese, The Pilleys of Borneo, Recollections of the Marshall Mission, Rush Me More Orphans, South Korea - Democracy or Dictatorship, South of Tokyo, Still the Rice Grains Green, The Story of Japan, We the People, What's it Like on Formosa, When Budda Came to Bathe, Untitled Manuscript (Box 14 - 21)
- Blurbs and Printed Weekly Series. Weekly serial stories for Sunday Digest and Sunday Pix. Arranged by chronology. Typewritten. China Coast Family, Terror by Night, The Tiger Hunter. Lecture Notes - Typewritten and holograph. 9 sets of lecture notes. (Box 22)
  Television and radio notes and addresses. Typewritten and chronologically arranged. One short undated announcement
  Questions and notes on Chiang Kai-shek. Sections of the General's diary and answers to Caldwell's questions.
  Passports and Authorization Papers - Papers are in English and Chinese. Typewritten.
- Publisher contracts and other legal documents. Arranged Chronologically. (Box 23)
  Southern Observer. Two copies which are arranged chronologically. Caldwell was the "Book
  Review Editor", or "Literary Editor".
  Book Reviews amd Book Advertisements. Undated or arranged by year.
  Lecture announcements and advertisements.
  Letters of U. S. soldiers to unwed mothers in Japan. Arranged chronologically.
- Photographs - 343 photographs of people, places, and things, photographed by Caldwell on his trips to Asia, South America, Europe, and Africa. Completed 2/10/69 (Box 24)
- Correspondence - Outgoing, January 27, 1966 - September 3, 1968. (Box 25)
  Outgoing correspondence of 252 letters. Chronologically arranged by days and months, letters are typescript and carbon copies. Four undated letters.
- Correspondence - Incoming. Incoming correspondence of 189 letters and 9 post cards. Alphabetically arranged, letters are typescript, holograph, and carbon copies. One letter without surname. (Box 25)
- Manuscripts, jacket copies, gallies, dummies, and miscellaneous notes. Material includes 18 typescript and carbon copies of manuscripts etc., alphabetically arranged. (Box 26 - 35)
  For Pacific Travel Guide; Let's Visit Afganistan; Let's Visit France; Let's Visit Italy; Let's Visit Malaysia; Let's Visit the Middle East; Let's Visit Russia; Let's Visit Scotland; Let's Visit South Africa; Let's Visit Southeast Asia; Let's Visit Thailand; Let's Visit Turkey; Let's Visit Vietnam; Massage Girl And Other Stories Of Thailand; Our Neighbors In Australia And New Zealand; Our Neighbors In Central America; Our Neighbors In Thailand; Tokyo Is...
- Book Reviews. Material consists of 4 reviews of Caldwell's books. Alphabetically arranged by author: James Conaway; William J. Curtis; Virginia Kirkus; Edith Weigle. (Box 36)
- Newspaper and magazine clippings. Approximately 15 clippings, dealing mainly with countries about which Caldwell has written. (Box 36)
- Photographs (31) (Box 36)
  Thirty-one photographs of people, places, and things in Asia, Central America, and Australia.
- Pamphlets (7) (Box 36)
- Miscellaneous. 2 calling cards; 2 records; several bills and receipts; a contract between John C. Caldwell and The John Day Company; a map of Central America. (Box 36)
- Correspondence - Outgoing, Feb. 21, 1963-Oct. 22, 1969 (Box 36)
  168 letters, typed. Nine undated letters in last folder. Listed alphabetically.
- Correspondence - Incoming (Box 36)
  Arranged according to date. One card and 95 letters. Includes 3 unidentified letters dated Aug. 12, 1968 to "John", Oct. 15 to "Roberta", April 9, 1968 to "Ruth and family."
- Manuscript Materials - original MSS, carbon copies, revisions, jacket copies, etc. (Box 37-40)
  Alphabetically arranged: Far Pacific Travel Guide, Let's Visit Afghanistan, Let's Visit Canada(Revisions, also from Japan, South Pacific, Venezuela, Brazil), LV Formosa (Revision, also for Turkey, West Indies), LV Ireland, LV Germany, LV India, LV Malaysia, LV Micronesia, LV Middle Africa, LV Middle East, LV Nigeria, LV Southeast Asia, LV the USA, LV West Africa, LV Yugoslavia, Massage Girl, New Travel Guide.
- Galleyproofs (6) (Box 41)
  LV the USA; LV West Africa; LV Malaysia; LV Micronesia
- Massage Girl - Galleyproofs (Box 42)
- Printed Dummies (7) (Box 43)
  LV Canada, LV Central America, LV Colombia, LV Middle Africa, LV Peru, LV Southeast Asia, LV West Indies Books - LV South Pacific, LV Southeast Asia; (cover of LV Nigeria)
- Business Agreements; Miscellaneous Magazine Clippings, Book reviews, Newspaper articles, Pictures in Massage Girl, Photographs, Brochures and Pamphlets, Miscellaneous. (Box 44)